NEO can now turn any prompt into autonomous
NEO는 이제 어떤 프롬프트든 자율적으로
action. With the latest update to the 1X
행동할 수 있습니다. 1X의 최신 업데이트로
World Model, NEO learns from internet-scale data
월드 모델을 통해 NEO는 인터넷 규모의 데이터에서 학습하고
and applies it to the real world.
이를 현실 세계에 적용합니다.
By visualizing future actions with a video model
물리 법칙에 기반한 비디오 모델로 미래의 행동을 시각화하면
grounded in physics, NEO can generalize to new
NEO는 처음 보는 새로운 작업에도
tasks it's never seen before. This opens a
일반화할 수 있습니다. 이는
new path for robotics learning, one where robots
로봇 학습의 새로운 길을 열어, 로봇이
learn by teaching themselves, using the data they
스스로를 가르치며 학습하고, 자신이 생성한 데이터를
generated on their own, and grow in AI
활용해 AI
capabilities alongside the rapidly improving video models.
역량을 빠르게 발전하는 비디오 모델과 함께 키워 나갑니다.
Our world model is pre-trained on web
저희 월드 모델은 웹에서 수집된
-scale video data that captures human interaction, and
인간 상호작용을 담은 인터넷 규모의 비디오 데이터로 사전 학습한 뒤
then post-trained on robot data to ground
로봇 데이터로 후속 학습을 수행해
that understanding in real-world physics and NEO's
그 이해를 현실 세계의 물리 법칙과 NEO의
humanoid embodiment. This allows NEO to visualize future
휴머노이드 몸체에 정착시킵니다. 이를 통해 NEO는 미래의
actions and use a built-in inverse dynamics
행동을 시각화하고 내장된 역동학 역모델을
model to turn those visualizations into movement.
사용해 그 시각화를 움직임으로 바꿉니다.
Today, we'll use the world model as NEO's
오늘은 월드 모델을 NEO의
cognitive core to execute autonomous action sequences several
인지 코어로 사용해 수 초 길이의 자율 행동 시퀀스를
seconds long.
실행해 보겠습니다.
How it works is you'll give NEO a
작동 방식은 NEO에게
prompt with voice or text. For this example,
음성이나 텍스트로 프롬프트를 주는 것입니다. 이번 예시에서는
I'll use the world model desktop interface to
월드 모델 데스크톱 인터페이스를 사용해
illustrate how it comes together. And start with
어떻게 구성되는지 보여드리겠습니다. 그리고
something simple, like having NEO pack this orange
이 오렌지를 도시락통에
into the lunchbox.
담게 하는 것처럼 간단한 예부터 시작하겠습니다.
Once you prompt NEO, it'll take what it
NEO에게 프롬프트를 주면 NEO는 자신이
sees as input to generate a visualization of
보고 있는 것을 입력으로 받아
how to complete the request. As you can
요청을 완료하는 방법의 시각화를 생성합니다. 보시는 것처럼
see on the screen below, NEO is visualizing
아래 화면에서 NEO는
how to perform this task using its world
자신의 월드 모델을 사용해 이 작업을
model.
수행하는 방법을 시각화하고 있습니다.
You can either have NEO automatically execute the
NEO가 생성 결과를 자동으로 실행하게 할 수도 있고
generation or choose the best one to run
여러 병렬 생성 중에서 실행할
from among several parallel generations.
가장 좋은 것을 골라 사용할 수도 있습니다.
While NEO has never seen these objects before,
NEO는 이 물체들을 본 적이 없지만,
there are still some examples of pick and
데이터셋에는 집어 들고
place tasks in our dataset. So one might
놓는 작업의 예시가 일부 있습니다. 그래서
assume it's generalizing to a similar task to
비슷한 작업으로 일반화해
create this visualization.
이 시각화를 만든다고 생각할 수 있습니다.
But this is not the case. With the
하지만 그렇지 않습니다. 월드 모델을 통해
world model, NEO can perform any task with
NEO는 어떤 작업이든
any object, whether there is existing data or
어떤 물체로도 수행할 수 있으며,
not.
기존 데이터가 있든 없든 상관없습니다.
Not only has NEO never seen this toilet,
NEO는 이 변기를 본 적이 없을 뿐 아니라,
but it has never performed a task anywhere
비슷하다고 할 만한 작업을
near similar. Without any prior data on how
수행한 적도 전혀 없습니다. 변기 시트를
to operate a toilet seat, the transfer of
조작하는 방법에 대한 사전 데이터가 없기 때문에
human knowledge becomes a lot more apparent.
인간 지식의 전이가 훨씬 더 분명해집니다.
The world model is also really useful for
월드 모델은 또한
handling unpredictable environments.
예측 불가능한 환경을 다루는 데 매우 유용합니다.
Traditional AI models for robots are often overly
로봇을 위한 전통적인 AI 모델은 종종 지나치게
sensitive to the surroundings, like changes in lighting
주변 환경에 민감합니다. 예를 들어 조명 변화나
or even random objects in the environment.
환경 속의 무작위 물체에도 그렇습니다.
NEO's world model, by contrast, applies human knowledge
반면 NEO의 월드 모델은 인간의 지식을 적용해
of how to navigate highly dynamic settings to
매우 역동적인 상황을 어떻게 헤쳐 나가는지에 대한 지식을 바탕으로
handle even the most extreme changes in environment.
환경의 가장 극단적인 변화까지도 처리합니다.
Given a world model can generate just about
월드 모델이 거의
anything you can imagine, there is no limit
상상할 수 있는 무엇이든 생성할 수 있으므로, 한계가 없고
to what NEO can try and execute autonomously.
NEO는 자율적으로 무엇이든 시도하고 실행할 수 있습니다.
While NEO's world model is trusted, they are
NEO의 월드 모델은 신뢰할 수 있지만,
consistentlyendre learning and successful watches in activity momento
활동하는 순간마다 지속적으로 학습하며 성공 여부를 관찰합니다.
inbetween.
그 사이에도 그렇습니다.
We still have work to do to increase
저희는 여전히 개선해야 할 부분이 있으며
the length and success rate of each generated
각 생성된 능력의 지속 시간과 성공률을 높여
ability
월드 모델을
to make the world model more useful.
더 유용하게 만들기 위한 할 일이 남아 있습니다.
But with the world model, NEO can create
하지만 월드 모델을 통해 NEO는
unlimited data of itself doing real-world tasks,
현실 세계의 작업을 수행하는 자신의 데이터를 무제한으로 만들 수 있고,
creating a flywheel that enables NEO to teach
NEO가 스스로를 가르치도록 하는 플라이휠을 만들며
itself anything, marking a true paradigm shift in
스스로 무엇이든 해낼 수 있게 되어, 이는 AI와 로보틱스 분야의
AI and robotics.
진정한 패러다임 전환을 의미합니다.